A new Marvel legend arrives.
Morbius is a action, science fiction, fantasy film directed by Daniel Espinosa.
Dangerously ill with a rare blood disorder, and determined
to save others suffering his same fate, Dr.
Michael Morbius attempts a desperate gamble.
What at first appears to be a radical success soon reveals itself
to be a remedy potentially worse than the disease.
Dr. Michael Morbius, played by Jared Leto.
Milo, played by Matt Smith.
Martine Bancroft, played by Adria Arjona.
Dr. Emil Nicholas, played by Jared Harris.
Agent Simon Stroud, played by Tyrese Gibson.
Agent Rodriguez, played by Al Madrigal.
Morbius is a 2022 American superhero film based on
the character from Marvel Comics.
Produced by Columbia Pictures in association with Marvel Entertainment, Arad Productions, and Matt Tolmach Productions,
and distributed by Sony Pictures Releasing it is the third film in Sony's Spider-Man Universe (SSU).
Jared Leto stars as Dr.
Michael Morbius, alongside Matt Smith, Adria Arjona, Jared
Harris, Al Madrigal, and Tyrese Gibson.
The film was directed by Daniel Espinosa and written
by Matt Sazama and Burk Sharpless.
In the film, Michael Morbius and his surrogate brother Milo (Smith) become
living vampires after curing themselves of a rare blood disease.
There were previously two notable attempts to adapt the character of Michael Morbius into a cinematic form since 1998, those being a role in the
Blade franchise as an antagonist and having a solo film produced by Artisan Entertainment, neither of which ever came to fruition.
After announcing plans for a new shared universe of films inspired by Spider-Man related
characters beginning with Venom (2018), Sony began developing a film based on Morbius.
Sazama and Sharpless had written a script by November 2017, and
Leto and Espinosa officially joined in June 2018.
Work on the film began at the end of the year with further casting,
ahead of production starting in London in February 2019.
Filming was confirmed to have been completed by June 2019, with
reshoots happening in Los Angeles the following February.
Jon Ekstrand was hired to compose the film's score.
Morbius premiered at the Plaza Carso in Mexico City on March 10, 2022, and was theatrically released in the United States on
April 1, after being delayed several times from an initial July 2020 date, primarily due to the COVID-19 pandemic.
The film was a critical and commercial failure, receiving criticism for the writing, visual
effects, and post-credits scenes, although Smith's performance received some praise.
The film grossed $167.5 million worldwide.
It became the subject of Internet memes mocking its reception and quality; the popularity of said memes led
Sony to re-release the film in theaters the following June, to another commercial failure.
It later received five Golden Raspberry Awards nominations, including Worst Picture, and
ended up winning Worst Actor for Leto and Worst Supporting Actress for Arjona.
The film explores themes of vampire, superhero, based on
comic, duringcreditsstinger, supervillain.
The tone is thought_provoking.